

SPENCER SUGARMAN

- SPENCERSUGARMAN.COM
- SPENCERSUGARMAN@GMAIL.COM
- (412)-254-4227

⚠ My biggest passion is user research, and I have four years of lab experience under my belt to back it up. These days I spend my hours working as a research programmer in the Department of Psychology at Carnegie Mellon University after recently completing my master's in human-computer interaction.

EXPERIENCE

Carnegie Mellon University Research Programmer, 2012—present

Developing a cross-platform mobile application using jQuery Mobile and Phonegap to assist second-language learners. Using Amazon's Mechanical Turk platform to perform psycholinguistic research for the Department of Defense. Providing streaming media and data collection services for researchers to train the next generation of clinical psychologists.

Carnegie Mellon University Research Associate, 2008—2012

Built an online system in PHP and JavaScript for exploring and analyzing transcripts in the world's largest corpus database of conversational speech. Transcribed and coded conversational interactions, and assisted in ongoing language experiments.

3M Company, MHCI Capstone Project, 2011

Worked for eight months in a small team to design a new product for the educational space the company's unique technological strengths. Performed user research to understand the needs of stakeholders. Built low- and high-fidelity hardware and software prototypes to test and convey design ideas. Provided appropriate documentation and design specifications.

Pittsburgh Post-Gazette, 2011

Worked with journalists, readers, and other locals to design a possible solution for increasing readership in light of recent industry disruptions. Designed an information hub with a focus on assisting recent transplants become acclimated to their new locale.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Opening Data, 2012—present

Building a platform to allow citizens and governments to better understand and address social problems by providing open data, engaging communities, developing tools for analyzing and presenting results, and offering assistance to groups interested in utilizing civic data. Currently seeking funding.

Undress Me Robot, 2004—2008

Designed layout based on current best practices and community feedback. Customized and managed Wordpress backend. Recruited contributors and provided editorial oversight on all submissions. Worked with media companies to obtain promotional material.

METHODS AND SKILLS

PHP, JavaScript, HTML5/CSS3, Adobe Creative Suite, Data Analysis, Prototyping, Contextual Design, Cognitive Walkthrough, Personas, Storyboarding, Heuristic Evaluation, Keystroke-Level Modeling, Affinity Diagramming

EDUCATION

Carnegie Mellon University, December 2011

Master of Human-Computer Interaction

University of Pittsburgh, May 2008

Bachelor of Science in Psychology